http://www.leckey.com/privacy-policy/

This website uses cookies. Please click "Accept and Close" to accept the use of cookies on our website. By continuing to browse our website you consent to the use of cookies on this website.
For more information on how we use cookies please visit our
Cookie Policy, or visit our Privacy Notice page
for more information on how we manage and use data.
Accept and close
Distributor Portal
My Leckey
Products
Products
Back
Go to Products
Seating
Leckey Privacy Policy
James Leckey Design Ltd is aware of its obligations under the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) and is committed to processing your data securely and transparently. This privacy notice sets out, in line with GDPR, the types of data that we hold. It also sets out how we use that information, how long we keep it for and other relevant information about your data.
1. Scope
This notice applies to individuals including (but not limited to) customers, suppliers, business contacts, client and any other individuals we have a direct or indirect relationship with. We have a separate Privacy Notice for our employees, contractors and agency workers.
2.
Data Controller Details
The Company is a data controller, meaning that it determines the processes to be used when using your personal data. Our contact details are as follows:
James Leckey Design Ltd19c Ballinderry RoadLisburn BT28 2SA E: hello@leckey.com Tel: 028 9260 0750
Firefly Friends Ltd 19c Ballinderry Road Lisburn BT28 2SAE: hello@fireflyfriends.com Tel: 028 9267 8879
If you are not happy with any aspect of how we collect and use your data, you have the right to complain to the Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO), the UK supervisory authority for data protection issues (www.ico.org.uk). We should be grateful if you would contact us first if you do have a complaint so that we can try to resolve it for you.
It is very important that the information we hold about you is accurate and up to date. Please let us know if at any time your personal information changes by emailing us at hello@leckey.com
3. How we use your personal data
We will only use your personal data when legally permitted. The most common uses of your personal data are:
Where we need to perform the contract between us.
Where it is necessary for our legitimate interests (or those of a third party) and your interests and fundamental rights do not override those interests.
Where we need to comply with a legal or regulatory obligation.
Generally, we do not rely on consent as a legal ground for processing your personal data, other than in relation to sending marketing communications to you via email. You have the right to withdraw consent to marketing at any time by emailing us at hello@leckey.com
4. Purposes for Processing your Personal Data
Set out below is a description of the ways we intend to use your personal data and the legal grounds on which we will process such data. We have also explained what our legitimate interests are where relevant.
We may process your personal data for more than one lawful ground, depending on the specific purpose for which we are using your data. Please email us at hello@leckey.com if you need details about the specific legal ground we are relying on to process your personal data where more than one ground has been set out in the table below.
Purpose/Activity
Type of Data
Lawful Basis for Processing
To register you as a new customer
(a) Identity
(b) Contact
Performance of a contract with you
To process and deliver your quote or order including:
(a) Manage payments, fees and charges
(b) Collect and recover money owed to us
(a) Identity
(b) Contact
(c) Financial
(d) Transaction
(e)Marketing and Communications
(a) Performance of a contract with you
(b) Necessary for our legitimate interests to recover debts owed to us
To manage our relationship with you which will include:
(a) Notifying you about changes to our terms or privacy policy
(b) Asking you to leave a review or take a survey
(a) Identity
(b) Contact
(c) Profile
(d) Marketing and Communications
(a) Performance of a contract with you
(b) Necessary to comply with a legal obligation
(c) Necessary for our legitimate interests to keep our records updated and to study how customers use our products/services
To enable you to partake in a prize draw, competition or complete a survey
(a) Identity
(b) Contact
(c) Profile
(d) Usage
(e) Marketing and Communications
(a) Performance of a contract with you
(b) Necessary for our legitimate interests to study how customers use our products/services, to develop them and grow our business
To administer and protect our business and our site (including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, system maintenance, support, reporting and hosting of data)
(a) Identity
(b) Contact
(c) Technical
(a) Necessary for our legitimate interests for running our business, provision of administration and IT services, network security, to prevent fraud and in the context of a business reorganisation or group restructuring exercise
(b) Necessary to comply with a legal obligation
To deliver relevant content and advertisements to you and measure and understand the effectiveness of our advertising
(a) Identity
(b) Contact
(c) Profile
(d) Usage
(e) Marketing and Communications
(f) Technical
(g) Photo
(h) Video
Necessary for our legitimate interests to study how customers use our products/services, to develop them, to grow our business and to inform our marketing strategy
Where the photos / video are of Children for purposed of case studies / case histories. Consent will be gained from the parent.
To use data and data analytics to improve our website, to develop products/service, to improve products/services, marketing, customer relationships and experiences
(a) Identity
(b) Contact
(c) Technical
(d) Usage
(e) Photo
(f) Video
(g) Bio and Health data
Necessary for our legitimate interests to define types of customers for our products and services, to keep our site updated and relevant, to develop our business and to inform our marketing strategy
Where the photos / video are of Children for purposed of case studies / case histories, consent will be gained from the parent.
Where the bio/health data of Children is collected for the purposes of product / service development and improvement, consent will be gained from the parent.
To make suggestions and recommendations to you about products or services that may be of interest to you
(a) Identity
(b) Contact
(c) Technical
(d) Usage
(e) Profile
Necessary for our legitimate interests to develop our products/services and grow our business
5. Marketing Communications
You will receive marketing communications from us if you have:
Requested information from us or purchased goods or services from us; or
If you provided us with your details and ticked the box at the point of entry of your details for us to send you marketing communications;
We will get your express opt-in consent before we share your personal data with any third party for marketing purposes. You can ask us or third parties to stop sending you marketing messages at any time by emailing us at hello@leckey.com at any time.
Where you opt out of receiving our marketing communications, this will not apply to personal data provided to us as a result of a product/service purchase, warranty registration, product/service experience or other transactions.
6. Disclosures of your personal data
We may have to share your personal data with the parties set out below for the purposes set out in the table in paragraph 2 above:
Service providers who provide IT and system administration services.
Professional advisers including lawyers, bankers, auditors and insurers who provide consultancy, banking, legal, insurance and accounting services.
HM Revenue & Customs, regulators and other authorities based in the United Kingdom and other relevant jurisdictions who require reporting of processing activities in certain circumstances.
Third parties to whom we sell, transfer, or merge parts of our business or our assets.
We require all third parties to whom we transfer your data to respect the security of your personal data and to treat it in accordance with the law. We only allow such third parties to process your personal data for specified purposes and in accordance with our instructions.
7. Data Security
We have put in place appropriate security measures to prevent your personal data from being accidentally lost, used or accessed in an unauthorised way, altered or disclosed. In addition, we limit access to your personal data to those employees, agents, contractors and other third parties who have a business need to know such data. They will only process your personal data on our instructions, and they are subject to a duty of confidentiality.
We have put in place procedures to deal with any suspected personal data breach and will notify you and any applicable regulator of a breach where we are legally required to do so.
8. Data Retention
We will only retain your personal data for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements.
To determine the appropriate retention period for personal data, we consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosure of your personal data, the purposes for which we process your personal data and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal requirements.
By law we have to keep basic information about our customers (including Contact, Identity, Financial and Transaction Data) for six years after they cease being customers for tax purposes. You can request our data retention table from hello@leckey.com
In some circumstances you can ask us to delete your data: see below for further information.
In some circumstances we may anonymise your personal data (so that it can no longer be associated with you) for research or statistical purposes in which case we may use this information indefinitely without further notice to you.
9. Your Legal Rights
Under certain circumstances, you have rights under data protection laws in relation to your personal data. These include the right to:
Request access to your personal data.
Request correction of your personal data.
Request erasure of your personal data.
Object to processing of your personal data.
Request restriction of processing your personal data.
Request transfer of your personal data.
Right to withdraw consent.
You can see more about these rights at: https://ico.org.uk/for-organisations/guide-to-the-general-data-protection-regulation-gdpr/individual-rights/
If you wish to exercise any of the rights set out above, please email us at hello@leckey.com.
You will not have to pay a fee to access your personal data (or to exercise any of the other rights). However, we may charge a reasonable fee if your request is clearly unfounded, repetitive or excessive. Alternatively, we may refuse to comply with your request in these circumstances.
We may need to request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity and ensure your right to access your personal data (or to exercise any of your other rights). This is a security measure to ensure that personal data is not disclosed to any person who has no right to receive it. We may also contact you to ask you for further information in relation to your request to speed up our response.
We try to respond to all legitimate requests within one month. Occasionally it may take us longer than a month if your request is particularly complex or you have made a number of requests. In this case, we will notify you and keep you updated.
Leckey Connect Privacy Policy
How we use your information
Leckey will use your information for the following purposes:
Enable therapists to interpret the data collected by the app to plan treatment goals and other therapeutic interventions for their clients
Leckey will use the data to understand the adherence to therapy regimes and look at how usage relates to disability and impairment levels
The information will help us capture trends in active therapy and my feed into future clinical programmes and product development
Information will be used to provide and maintain app service, including the future development of the app’s key features
Information may be used to communicate with its users through push notifications where enabled
How information is shared
Anonymised data may be shared to 3rd party researchers after seeking ethical approval from the University or NHS for a research project. The information would be used to research the effectiveness of the intervention but not for product development.
Information We Collect
Leckey will collect the following types of information, in line with our data collection and retention policy.
This information includes but is not limited to; Child or Therapist Name (only visible to Super Users and not visible to researchers), Date of Birth, Gender, Diagnosis, GMFCS, GMFM Assessment Date, Lying and Rolling %, Sitting %, Crawling and kneeling %, Standing %, Walking. Running and jumping %, Session #, Date of session, Start time, Stop time, Duration, Total distance, Average speed (RPM), top speed (RPM), Speed events, Therapist email address, Guardian email address.
Data Retention
We keep your account information, like your name and email address, for as long as your account is in existence because we need it to operate your account.
Accounts which remain dormant for 12 month or more will be contacted and given 30-days’ notice before closure of their account. You can reply to the notification within the 30 days to request the account remains open. After 30 days, the account and the data stored in this account will be deleted.
At times we may anonymise your personal data (so that it can no longer be associated with you) for research or statistical purposes in which case we may use this information indefinitely without further notice to you.
Users may delete individual clients and their data within your account by selecting ‘Delete Child’ within the child’s profile.
Users may delete their account and the data associated with the app by contacting us at connectsupport@leckey.com detailing your user email address. A member of the support team will reply to let you know that your request has been completed.
Available in 20+ countries
We work closely with over 20+ global partners who distribute the Leckey family of products throughout the world.
To get in touch or to become a Leckey distributor, please email hello@leckey.com or call us on (+44) 28 9260 0750.
Find A Distributor
Stay Connected
Sign up to our mailing list or connect with us on our social media channels.
Join our list
Stay Connected
Name
Email
Please tick here to give us consent to store your details for our mailing list.
